welcome to the first
talk in the small theater theater
7 I'm pleased to introduce without any
extra words Jeffrey capab biano from
Moody who has so much to tell us he
needs all the minutes
product manager of search uh for
moodys.com
turn that down a bit very excited to be
here because hyack has been a big
inspiration for me over the few past few
years more recently I've had the honor
of contributing to the Moody's research
assistant which is a chat application
for financial
analysis it's been an amazing
collaboration of multiple teams working
at a very fast pace and though it's
cliche we like to say that it takes a
village so we'll help you lay out a plan
to create a
transformational retrieval augmented
generation application in a short period
of
time let's start with a
story our story at Moody's begins with a
very talented and driven AI Whisperer by
the name of sahill hosani and sahill
worked late into the night building a
chat application that accepts free form
questions and responds using Moody's
Data before long both leadership and
investors alike became very excited
about this easy to use delightful
experience and maybe more importantly
its time-saving implications for our
users so
the search Squad joined forces with the
research assistance Squad so we could
work together on scalability and
iterating on answer
quality which brings us du today the
Moody's research assistant is live in
production with a growing amount of
traffic and a growing number of paid
subscribers it can answer a wide range
of questions about organizations their
credit ratings financial data and
broad-based sector
questions it provides citations relevant
charts and suggests follow-up questions
to guide your research
Journey so we'll share some of the
knowledge we gathered along the way and
some of these lessons came from Quick
wins others are from the benefit of
hindsight hopefully will help you avoid
learning some lessons the hard
way we'll go over this in four main
sections first nobody likes a solution
in search of a problem problem so we'll
give you some tools to help explain your
stakeholders the value of
rag then we'll all get on the same page
about what a system like this may look
like some of the big uh building blocks
to which we'll refer back throughout the
talk and then part three is going to be
the main portion where we talk about
setting a foundation the things you
should invest in early on so you can
iterate quickly on top and then very
briefly we'll talk about some areas you
can explore next and build on top of
that Foundation
so why would you build a retrieval
augmented generation
app I'm guessing I'm not the only one of
us to learn that CEOs really want Ai and
then it's up to us to figure out how to
make it
work there's a deoe study which I'll
reference in the appendix that shows
eight out of 10 leaders expect AI to
transform their organization within
three
years and rag can be a wonderful bridge
between that desire and real value for
your users and therefore your business
so here you can see our credit an
analyst with a big stack of relevant
data that we provided from moodies and
instead of reading through this wide
swath of data and synthesizing a
response for their needs the research
assistant does that for them and
automates one more step of their Journey
so especially in our businessto business
setting Time Savings is the real product
and research assist users save up to 27%
of their time performing financial
analysis so that frees them up to do
higher value
tasks and you get that time savings
through this easy to use tailored chat
experience that's rooted in our factual
trusted data and we enable this by
getting The Best of Both Worlds between
a search engine and a large language
model what do we mean by Best of Both
Worlds well the search engines it's a
Well studied problem of getting
upto-date information indexed into your
system as it's
published and that data your indexing
probably sets your business apart from
others with an llm by itself it's very
challenging to train new data and new
information into that model it takes
money for compute it takes time to
complete you need a high level of
expertise to do it
effectively and even once you train it
with that data can still give responses
that are outside of those facts it can
still
hallucinate now in some applications
this generated these generated musings
from large language models can be really
powerful if you think of things like
image generation creative writing
brainstorming you wouldn't even call
this hallucination it's a it's a great
feature of the
llm but for us we need to provide
trusted data from industry experts so AI
really needs to stick to the fact facts
that we
provide sometimes when I'm interacting
with an llm all on its own it kind of
makes me think of uh some trouble I
would get into when I was younger I was
a very confident young guy and uh when I
was asked a question I didn't know the
answer I instead of saying I don't know
I would this sounds plausible maybe it's
right and I would give my confident
answer and people would often believe me
and then before long I would get into
trouble for that and you can get
yourself in the same trouble if you try
to train a model and send that out in
the world and and represent your company
you know there have been some cases in
the airline industry in automotive
retail where there have been real
financial and reputational damage
because chat Bots uh went off the
script so mitigating and preventing
Hallucination is a key component of
rag going back to the search engines as
we saw in the image users need to
synthesize a response together from a
lot of sources and for those of us
building the search engines getting the
full user context can be very
challenging need to master a lot of
techniques Wrangle a lot of data with
llms they're very context aware and they
can answer very specific questions right
out of the box so by retrieving data
from a search engine and then generating
a response with an llm we aim to get all
of these desired behaviors and leave
behind some of the
drawbacks we get some net new benefits
as well we spoke about about the
synthesis element and we can also
suggest follow-up questions to which you
know you have the answer because you
generate them from your
data but it comes with new challenges as
well these systems have a number of
moving parts that all need to work in
Con on in concert and measuring that
Ensemble can be very difficult we'll
talk about that in
detail so I'm sure there are a lot of
use cases uh for rag but from our
perspective it's very focused on freeing
up knowledge workers for more high value
tasks and so if your business check some
of these boxes there's probably a good
case for rag for
you so how do you actually make a system
like this work we'll go over some of the
main building blocks starting at the top
with our chat interface of which we saw
the screen recording a few slides ago a
user can answer any question they'd like
any prompt they'd like and the first
step along that that question's Journey
is this intent detection layer this box
is green to denote the opportunities to
use large language
models and this intent detection layer
can make your search engin job a lot
easier it can filter down your space it
can route different kinds of questions
the best suited data
sources and so it's going to send uh
queries to your search engine to your
structured data databases and apis and
this little Trio in the bottom left here
makes up the retrieval portion that R in
rag it needs to be able to handle long
queries it needs to get relevant chunks
of data that can fit into the large
language models context window that Max
number of tokens it can accept in a
prompt so once you've retrieved your
relevant chunks you bundle them together
into a prompt you send them to a large
language model in this response
generation step like GPT or Claude and
then you stream your response back to
the user
so everyone's on board with the value
proposition you know the high level
architecture where should you focus
first we're going to talk about laying a
foundation for fast iteration and some
upfront Investments that can save you
time down the
road we're going to talk about four
cornerstones to tackle
early one understanding cost this could
be the most expensive software to run at
your
company two
measuring this Ensemble of inputs and
outputs so that you avoid a one step
forward one step back relevance tuning
experience three we'll talk about
detecting intent which for us at Moody
has been one of the most crucial aspects
to Our
Success llms unlock big opportunities in
this
area and fourth preventing
hallucinations so you gain your users
trust and you leverage your
differentiating
data so understanding
costs I want to help you avoid an
uncomfortable spot where your project
has progressed along only to realize
it's not financially sustainable for
your
business on the other hand maybe you
have colleagues who've had a knee-jerk
reaction that an ai ai application is
too expensive to run and you can do some
estimations to help them
understand there be one or two areas of
new cost in your stack if you don't have
an app like this today
the big one is large language model
providers these boxes in green companies
like open Ai and
anthropic and if you're not doing dense
Vector search today and you certainly
don't have to do it in order to build a
rag application but if you want to add
that into your stack then creating
embedding those numerical
representations of your data uh that's
going to be a new source of cost as
well apis like GPT and Claude they
charge per token and they have their own
tokenizers open AI website has this
tokenizer tool where you can paste in
chunks of data prompts responses from
llms and understand how many tokens they
contain and you can see It'll color code
them for you which is which is nice to
help you gain some
intuition and the tokens you send in the
prompt are priced differently than the
ones that come back in generation you
can see some examples from uh open a and
anthropic where generally the the
generated tokens cost twice as much as
the ones you send in a prompt so a
pretty simple formula emerges you need
to know the the number of tokens in your
prompt multiply it by that price and the
number of tokens you expect back in the
response multiply by that price and you
can even set hard limits on the number
of tokens that come back in your
response through these
apis so let's look at an example just to
get some numbers you'll need to look at
your use case and your data to to pick
token volumes estimates but let's say
use a 4,000 token prompt that's going to
contain your instructions to the model
your retrieved chunks and the user's
actual question and expect around 300
tokens to come back that's our box on
the right the response generation and
you probably have a smaller intent
detection prompt let's say it's 300
tokens and gives back a small 30 token
Json so you sum those up and then you
can start looking at the different
providers and the models they
offer you can see how a larger smarter
model like Claude 3 Opus or GPT 4 Turbo
are going to cost between $40 and $60
every 1,000 requests to your application
using the token volumes we estimated and
a smaller faster model like ha coup or
3.5 turbo are going to cost between $1
and $2 so there's a really big
difference there so it's worth spending
some time experimenting to find the
smallest fastest cheapest model that can
give you the accuracy you need and you
can mix and match for different use
cases maybe use a large smart model for
your final generation a small fast model
for your intent
detection you want to leave some
Headroom in these to volume estimates
the number of requests because you're
going need to do development
experimentation automated testing you
might want to add more tokens to a more
complex intent detection
layer and then the other portion we
spoke about is Vector uh creating your
embeddings in vectors and again you
don't need it it's not a must but for us
we found it was very helpful for these
long question like queries and for out a
vocabulary words so we decided to add it
into our stack uh and if you do the same
you'll need to create embeddings for
your chunked up data that you ingest and
also of the queries that are sent to
your
system most of your costs will come
whenever you rewrite a large volume of
data into your into your vector
database so you should set very clear
expectations with your business around
how much will cost to rewrite everything
what's the smallest valuable set of data
we can make searchable to start because
if you change your model to create
embeddings or you change you Chunk Up
the data you need to rewrite everything
and that's going to be the biggest cost
Source if you use uh third party
provider like coh here or open AI it's
again a per token pricing model it's
much less expensive than generation but
if you need more flexibility there are
tools like Sage maker where you could
host your own model uh you can use an
open source one you can train your own H
it's very flexible for different latency
needs for us at Moody's we're committed
to making data searchable 15 minutes
after it's published so we need strong
guarantees on throughput and we've been
experimenting with the server list batch
transform and real time options from
Sage
maker so your business understands the
estimated costs based on the volume of
data you
estimated it's time to start building
let's move to the second Cornerstone
which is measurement
if I could go back in time I would have
started this observ observability aspect
even earlier than we did and we started
it pretty
early if search relevance can be a game
of whack-a-mole you fix one query
another breaks over here rag can be like
the 3D chess of wack-a-mole because
there's just so many moving pieces in
concert and as I learned more about
measuring rag systems this image of
probes kept coming into my
mind by a show of hands anybody having
electrical engineering background either
professionally or
education okay nice I personally ran for
the hills of software immediately after
clawing through my e degree but I
digress uh the goal is to really enable
rapid experimentation with this approach
so you can iterate much faster and we're
going to talk about some of those
windows you need into your flow so that
you can keep making improvements without
regression first end to end see we got
our negative Probe on the the question
from the user our positive Probe on the
final generated response so you'll need
to measure the relevance of these to
these
pairs this is what matters to your user
so it should be a crucial checkpoint
before you release the
production but when problems arise it's
probably going to leave you with more
questions than answers so you need to
measure the intermediary steps as well
moving along our circuit here the next
step is that intent detection layer and
this will probably have a number of
steps depending on the queries you
expect and how your data looks you
should measure each one individually as
well as The Ensemble and depending on
your use case a lot of these are
probably measured like a
classifier now this one's crucial this
is when we learned the hard
way you have to have a test that looks
at the full retrieval phase I don't
think I need to tell the Hy stack
audience how important it is to measure
your search engine and isolation but
it's not sufficient
if you just look at the search engine
phase you could end up measuring queries
that are actually different than the
ones you'll receive in production
missing some pre-processing step or
maybe you're spending time optimizing
queries that are actually just routed
over to a a relational database or
something so having this full Ensemble
tested together the input from the user
and then the retrieve chunks that come
from this whole Trio here is crucial and
your teams will be able to iterate a lot
faster if they understand how these
layers
interact also if your test bed can
accept changes from both you'll be able
to experiment in
parallel so it's a bit of a Twist on the
the query doc pair measurement that we
know so well you know large language
models can't really scroll or paginate
they have one chunk of data they can
accept and they're prompt and they
actually have some capabilities to
discern
relevance so your goal is to fill the
context window with relevant chunks of
data and for this task I think Precision
at K is a great primary
metric but it's always important to
avoid having blinders on gaming one stat
and getting a holistic view of your
system so having some ranking aware
stats like err is really valuable as
well if you think about this border you
know at the end of the context window if
you swap the ranking of a good and bad
result there that could be a big
difference maker in your final response
and lastly you want to look at how
faithful your generated response from
the final llm stays to the chunks you
retrieved right people want your
proprietary data want your
differentiating data they don't want
something that came out of a foundation
model that has a low barrier to
entry there's a number of tools out
there to measure these kinds of systems
I'll probably have a new LinkedIn
message when I go back to the hotel this
evening about one that came out you
could build your own one of them is Lang
Smith is a screenshot from their
evaluation tool and you can see these
columns on the right represent the steps
we just spoke about the overall score
how faithful the response is to your
retrieved data and the quality of your
retrieved data and whatever tool you
choose or build needs to be able to run
batches of queries and you need to be
able to see performance at those
different stage
stages and again setting up your code to
work with your your test bench early can
save you time in the long run because
it's always hard to make time to
refactor once your codee's out in the
wild so you may have noticed that this
is a very data hungry
problem there's a large number of steps
that need annotations or
judgments and in my case I'm certainly
not an expert on financial analysis or
credit products but we still need to
support that domain as a
team and our search engine our pre
search engine wasn't really optimized
for question answering so we didn't have
a lot of implicit data to go off
of so we needed to work with our experts
their time's expensive they have other
deadlines and incentives to worry about
and when we can get their time this
question and long answer judgment is
much more mentally taxing and time
consuming than looking at a keyword in a
document title for
example plus since we're chunking up our
data just the number of Poss possible
pairs that needs annotations is really
large so we use a large language model
as a proxy it's not an expert but it can
save you a lot of time and if your
business and you understand the risks it
can be very
valuable again here's a screenshot from
the Lang Smith Tool they have a hub
feature which has a community uh
providing different prompts for
different tasks you can create a private
Hub just for your your business and you
can create your own custom prompts to
fit your domains which is what we did
also you can consider adding a relevant
scoring element right into your final
generation prompt it's going to increase
your production tokens a little bit it
needs to say super simple so you don't
confuse the main task so it's not
something you can WR rely on for fine
grained relevance scoring but it can be
a really nice coar grained indicator
that there's a class of problems that
are going not not going well or class of
queries that you're not answering well
even if users don't give you that
explicit feed back and it's really
really easy to incorporate this into
your logging versus separate offline
process but if if I can get another show
of hands who is skeptical about trusting
an llm to say whether you're doing a
good job whether relevance improves or
or
decreases okay less than I thought
there's some Believers out there well we
were really paranoid about it we didn't
know if it was going to understand the
financial language the task at hand was
the time savings worth the accuracy
risk so we did a one time time
exercise where we worked with our
experts to provide annotations on
different problems and then we sought to
answer the question does the AI agree
with the experts at least as well as
they agree with each other and you can
use some stats like Cohen's Kappa to
measure this but we found one of the
best ways to get everyone on the same
page is plotting out that
data so this is for a particular query
chunk relevance um judgment set and you
can see there's three labels that the
experts or the The llm Prompt could
provide that's bad fair or good
012 and each bar is a different judge
the red one is our our prompt and the
vertical is the number of annotations
they provided over the whole data set
for each
category and you can see that the AI is
much more likely to give a so so answer
than the experts were so you can regroup
your data to improve agreement now this
is going with a strict approach strict
meaning that bad or Fair we put those
together and we only care about
improving good chunks which like we said
that's our primary objective so we lose
some information about those incremental
improvements and regressions between bad
and fair but we're okay with that
because our goal is to get all good
chunks and it gives us better trust in
our automated offline
system but what if no matter how you
regroup the data you just can't get the
the experts and the the llm to
agree well there are a few prompt
engineering tricks that really helped
us and one of the biggest needle movers
was making sure that the prompt explains
and then
scores a large language model is picking
the most likely token generating the
most likely token one after another and
so if it gives you a judgment and then
an explanation it's just going to
justify that token it already generated
where if you use these Chain of Thought
techniques you tell it to think step by
step provide an explanation first it has
a bit more logic to go off of and we
found this was the biggest change in
getting our our llm prompt to agree with
our
experts also you can provide some few
shot examples with uh explanations from
your experts on why they judge certain
query chunk Pairs and you should give
similar instructions to the model that
you gave to the humans so your most
crucial Cornerstone zone is set you can
diagnose issues you can measure
Improvement you can see which pieces of
your system need the most
work let's talk about the two more key
components to your
foundation now a lot of papers and blogs
that I've personally read seem to gloss
over this intent dete detection
component but it's been one of the most
crucial aspects to Our Success on the
Moody's research
assistant l Ms are making a lot of these
techniques much easier than they've ever
been before you know full Tech search is
hard which I think is why a lot of us
enjoy it you can use some clever
prompting to thin out your search space
as much as possible we were able to make
the search engines job so easy that we
went to Market with open source
off-the-shelf embedding models that we
did not
fine-tune also you can work with your
colleagues who know where do I find the
answers to certain types of questions in
our data and you can encode that
knowledge into your
prompts let's look at an example here's
a use case we absolutely need to support
as users is asking about a particular
organization's credit
rating and they want to know how it
changed and why it changed so let's look
at three different queries we could use
to retrieve this
data one we could look at our Corpus of
expert research long form research from
Financial experts broken up into chunks
millions of
chunks and you can just create an
embedding of the initial question from
the user do a K&N search using open
search in an attempt to improve
Precision we could add a filter to that
query where you're only looking at
documents that are tagged with that
organization's ID from the
question or three could do away with all
the finicky Natures of full text search
write a SQL query to our r ratings
database where where it equals where we
have an ID in a particular column and
sort by a
date if I get one two or three
fingers which query do you think is
going to most reliably get our ratings
data three I see a lot of Threes I agree
I agree that where Clause is going to be
much more predictable than any full text
search technique but it's not going to
give you that context from the experts
that our users wanted
so again one two or three which C you
think is going to most reliably I see
some quick answers I love it which one
you think is most reliably going to get
our context yeah number two we'll filter
out noise about other companies and
we'll get the most relevant chunks about
the task at
hand so you can combine different data
sources to make that magical AI
experience but how do you structure
these queries or how do you construct
them rather
well I want to call back to one of my
favorite hay stacks from 2022 if you
haven't seen it go check it out on
YouTube boan bobich spoke about AI
driven search I was I am very impressed
with NEX door's architecture and how
they incorporate context into the
query with techniques like query
expansion name dentity recognition query
classification these techniques are very
powerful but they're also challenging
you need to Wrangle data train models
and deploy them out into to
production with llms you're able to
LeapFrog a lot of these difficult
tasks because prompt engineering is just
a really accessible art and it requires
a lot less expertise in training
models now this approach is going to
come at a cost we spoke about the
financial aspect it'll probably be
slower than something purpose-built for
your task but you can get to Market very
quickly and now you've set a benchmark
for your purpose-built systems
I just want to reiterate that baking
this kind of technology in early was
crucial to Our Success about that
magical AI experience and getting to
Market really
fast let's move on to our fourth
Cornerstone guarding against
hallucinations you want to avoid our app
acting like that overconfident teenage
boy right our users at Moody's need
factual financial information from
experts
not an llm generated response it's very
important to them we need their trust
and the the system needs to be able to
say I don't know when the answer is not
in your
data open aai provides a full prompt
engineering guide and we're going to
talk about a couple of these that are
important for that final response
generation
step first use delimiters in your prompt
to the model so it's really obvious here
are your instructions here's the
reference data here's the user's
question make it easy make it
unambiguous now this one's crucial so
important you need to explicitly tell
the model to only use your reference
test text and if it's the answer is not
in there say I don't know if you think
about the broad swath of data llms are
trained on there aren't that many how-to
articles or blog posts where someone
asks a question and then there's a
response I don't know right after it's
just not what they've seen so you need
to instruct it explicitly and this is a
slightly doctored example from open AI
but it's very optimistic about the
performance of a single short
instruction so you'll need to get a
little creative and not be afraid to be
heavy-handed to make sure it's only
sticking to your
data lastly it's another small step from
there to
um reference the citations uh the the
cited data has to be a particular format
so your UI can recognize it make it
really easy for users to click back and
forth to the source data
these apis are going to provide a
temperature parameter like we said it's
generating the next most likely token a
high temperature is going to add some
Randomness into that selection and
sampling of tokens so a high temperature
could make a more robotic or less
robotic more creative sounding response
but we're not after creativity we're a
after a faithful response to our data so
you'll probably want a temperature of
zero or very close to zero
this is a rapidly developing field with
lots of resources I mentioned the open
AI guide here's a few others you could
check
out so your foundation is
set you understand the costs you can
measure improvements diagnose issues and
prioritize different parts of your
system that need work and you understand
the user's intent and the responses
you're giving back are faithful to that
data that makes your business
special so it's time to get feedback as
quickly and with as little risk as
possible your app should be able to
accept feedback
directly and you can take this feedback
from your content creators from your
salespeople from your data experts and
encode that back into your intent
detection
prompts just like the offline testing we
discussed it's important to log all of
these inputs and outputs so that you can
see where things are going wrong maybe
you'll see a question from a few weeks
ago that still looks broken but it turns
out it's broken for a different reason
so you prevent yourself going on some
wild goose chases and then you can
prioritize and iterate but you should
definitely be careful about overfitting
to your internal users because if your
experiences anything like ours uh your
subscribers will ask novel things you
could have
anticipated and once you've set this
Foundation there's a few areas that you
could explore I think it's really
tempting to Dive Right into some of
these more Advanced Techniques but you
really don't need to fine-tune a model
or rerank if you have a really effective
intent detection system at least that
was true for us this approach is all
about getting something usable getting
feedback and taking it to the next level
so for us uh on the Moody's research
assistant we're about halfway down this
list right now and we're very curious
and optimistic about lm's capabilities
to choose the most relevant
chunk out of a list like a human
would all the images in this talk were
generated using Microsoft's co-pilot
designer tool and all of the studies and
resources are linked here so thank you
so much for listening thank you for the
time and uh any questions are
[Applause]
welcome thank you Jeff
thank you
Jeff okay let's try that one more time
you D and for
those playing along in the zoom version
of the game please type your questions
in the chat box I'll be moving through
the audience with the microphone as
quickly as possible starting down
here uh thank you great great talk um
really quite informative um I have lots
of questions so I'm going to I'm going
to choose two
uh for prime time um the first one is uh
is uh is something that you mentioned
about um about the your metrics said
it's important to look at Precision at K
right not recall or
err and um you know you know as we've
been working with customers I'm from
Aaron um we found that um you know
looking at recall U works pretty well
and so I'm just curious as to as to why
um why Precision in your particular use
case um so that's first question the
second okay sure that that's all I got
sure yeah I I definitely don't espouse
an approach where you only look at one
metric you should always have a sweet
that's something that um Ella yakoba
taught me back during our training you
want to avoid those blinders so you have
a full picture but I think it's
important to have one primary objective
that you can use to really measure um
your Improvement and if that one's not
met you know you might want to rethink
what you're doing and the reason I think
about Precision at K is cu you have this
limited space to fill and the goal is to
get them all quality results and no
matter what you do well context windows
are growing larger and larger with new
models but you're always going to have a
limit to what you can fit so that's why
I believe that pre that Precision metric
is important because there is like a a
maximum size you can fit bill so you
want to try to get every single chunk
that you fit into that prompt high
quality but I I definitely don't say you
should ignore recall I just think it
should be more of a secondary
stat coming from Alexandra fenberg how
do you deal with
latencies isn't the several stages
system too slow for
users yeah it it's definitely less
Speedy than a traditional search
experience and we still have our search
experience for those people who need
information really fast with maybe a bit
more of a straightforward information
need so we have some animations on the
screen while the mult the steps are are
calculating ahead of time and then we
also stream the response to users so as
soon as that final generation step
starts users are getting feedback and
can start
reading also those earlier llm steps we
have been looking a lot uh at smaller
faster models like Hau they're cheaper
and they go a lot faster than something
like GPT 4.5 turbo or or CLA
Opus great talk thanks you um just
wanted to ask about you know some of the
actual engineering behind this project
you know like some of the tools that
were used specifically when you're
talking about generating vectors for the
whole data set to do rag um what did you
use to get to to generate them to get
them into your search index I've been
the experience that sometimes that can
be the longest um part of a project is
actually generating those vectors and if
you have to change your your chunking
strategy or your model reprocessing that
so just curious like what do those
iterations look like how was that
experiened for you yeah great question
so we use off-the-shelf uh open source
model which to be Frank has become a
little outdated at this point and we're
getting ready to experiment with some
newer ones we we use AWS sag maker to
host the model so we don't have to worry
about so much of the the hosting
overhead and and
administrative and yeah like I said it's
really important to try to keep your
data set small at first that way the
time and and financial cost of rewriting
everything if you try a new model if you
break your chunks up in a different way
which has been really important for us
you know you can optimize that chunking
for retrieval and for the generation you
could even decouple those
things um and so yeah we found that
there's a few different options from
Sage maker that we've been playing
around with you know the the hatch
inference and serverless have been
really good options for our ingestion
and then the real time options are good
for the faster requirements of query
embedding so um yeah it was it was very
largely built around sag maker and then
using a lot of our standard relevance
Tools Plus some new ones we built
ourselves to just look at that query
chunk
relevance and from hob shidu it's from
experience do you have any tips on how
to avoid overfitting to internal
users well you have to time limit your
your internal beta for sure and you have
to take a good look at you know the
questions which are coming commonly and
then work with your business experts to
know if this is something a real user
might ask and before you go optimizing
for those it might be time to get some
paid beta users or you know free beta
but external users so you start to get
those questions from your real use cases
as quickly as possible but there's no
way to know what your real users are
going to ask until until you let them
in um how do you prompt for um query
intent so you said you you want to
determine what the user's intent is with
what the query intent is but what is
your prompt do you use functions do you
use uh plain
language ah good question good question
getting dangerously close to the secret
sauce so I'll have to be careful about
what I tell and you know you can talk to
me about joining moodies if you want to
know know more but generally we want to
take the pieces of information that are
crucial to many different types of
questions let the llm extract those and
then we use those as inputs to our other
systems like the search engine like our
apis uh and we generally go with the
approach of just getting more data and
there's different schools of thought out
there about you know whether you should
only fetch what you need or you could
fetch everything and then have a
postprocessing step to thin down to the
most valuable uh both have some pros and
cons uh but generally it's pretty plain
language and Json
responses uh great talk so I'm wondering
you are saying about combining the
structure data uh with search engine
right so how do you handle that that do
you do it for every question and what do
you do like you know do you call search
and structure that and then
postprocessing them I'm a little bit
curious about that sure sure good
question let me um just pull up that
slide so like I said you want to pull
out these pieces of information that are
crucial for a lot of parts of your
questions and then you can use those as
inputs to your systems like your search
engine your apis your
databases if you try to choose only the
ones that will matter for that question
up front do some kind of like question
classification that's one approach it'll
definitely you know save you some round
trips and some latency but it can have
some negative recall impacts versus if
for every system that you able to glean
an input you go fetch the data and then
you have something that postprocesses
maybe another prompt small model um you
know it's a bit bit more heavy weight
but more uh risk averse on hurting your
recall
pardon
me so I had a couple on this
side yeah so uh you referred one of the
slides regarding the using llm
for to judge the relevance offline right
mhm so would you like to add anything on
why not using LM
for measuring the relevance or measuring
the uh final response online so for
example when the user is asking a
question using the llms llm as the uh
judge based upon that reiterating the
answer or checking for another retriever
type so that you get some other answer
and then improvising the answers just
online when the query is happening was
there any experiments be behind that
sure yeah we we actually do that
actively there is a relevant scoring uh
component to our final generation prompt
but you're going to have to keep it so
so simple so that you don't confuse the
llm about what what its main task is
which is synthesizing response based on
your
chunks and keeping it really simple is
going to prevent you from you know
techniques like this where you have it
give a a big explanation and then uh uh
you know you give it lots of few shot
examples so so an offline process that
doesn't slow down your user experience
and doesn't add to your production token
volume can be really powerful to get
that more fine grained relevance
scoring where this more of like a an
online
approach right there in your response
generation is more of like an alert
signal like whoa whoa whoa a bunch of
these are coming back with terrible
scores uh what's going on here what's
this class of problem and it's not going
to be able to give you
um like that fine grained this one got a
little better this one got a little
worse also it's just super easy to add
into the prompt so I do recommend that
because you can just you know log it
right along all alongside of all your
other data but it's a much more complex
to build a system that for every real
user query you do this full offline
process um we might invest in that soon
but um yeah I think I think a blend of
the two can give you that accurate
and that ease of implementation
balance okay I have two questions left
in the time we
have thanks uh quick followup on the
query intent detection um does that to
for you does that involve any retrieval
do you use facet data or any kind of
classification of the query before you
uh try to do the do the query
intent there is some retrieval involved
um especially like identif Ying certain
named
entities um and yeah so it's all about
kind of isolating those data points that
are going to be important to filter down
your
space and our final
question great presentation thank you um
I had a question about the response
generation so you showed a list of
different uh llms that could potentially
be used do you do something where you
potentially send some queries to the
more expensive models and then others to
the cheaper ones based on like previous
learnings and then maybe you can do a
test like that and have like a tiered
system of like this is really
complicated this goes to gp4 this is a
really simple question this goes to Hau
to save money yeah we have done that
with different steps of the process
where we mix and match different models
and it's definitely has big speed and
cost implications of doing that however
for the final response generation we
like to stay consistent so it's not like
a jarring experience there's kind of one
voice you can expect back from the the
research assistant and we're very very
cautious about changing out that model
for that final step so that it stays
consistent thank you Jeff thank you
David thank you everyone we have 15
minutes until the next talk thank
everybody